We've seen so far how to send data from an end-device to the Network Server.
First, the end-device sends a packet to a gateway.
Then, the gateway transfers it on the Internet to a Network Server and an Application Server.
That's it.
The LoRaWAN protocol stops here.
From this point, we have the user data decrypted. In the LoRaWAN protocol,
this user data is called the frame payload.
If your Network Server provides a more secure environment with end-to-end security, you might have
a different architecture, but it doesn't change the overall explanation.
Indeed, you Application Server use to decrypt your data with the Application Session Key would be on
the same location as your IoT platform.
But really, what we're going to explain would be exactly the same.
The question is now, what are we going to do with this data?
Because we've set up a successful LoRaWAN transmission, and for that, we can be very glad indeed.
But now, we need to give some value to this data:
We want to save everything in the database.
We want to perform calculation, prediction and possibly to apply Artificial Intelligence.
We want to present things in tables, graphs or anything that suits our clients.
And finally, we want to make these data available through a web service. So the user will be able to
access and visualize these data from anywhere.
Great.
So, the good news is that this chapter is completely independent from the LoRa modulation and the LoRaWAN
standards we have studied so far.
That means that the following explanation can be easily transposed to any other protocols related to
the Internet of Things.
Okay, so before starting, let's remind some basic vocabulary:
- A frame that comes from the end device, and
that  goes to the network server.
then to the Iot platform is called a uplink frame.
And,
-A  the frame that comes from the IoT platform and that goes to the LoRaWAN server,
then towards the end-device is called a downlink frame.
Great.
We already saw everything concerning the LoRaWAN protocol in the previous chapter.
So, now we want to deal with the dialogue between the LoRaWAN server and the IoT platform.
And in this chapter, we're going to see in details two protocols which are HTTP and MQTT.
For now, we are just focusing only on the data transmission on the IoT platform.
But later in this course, we'll build a complete IoT platform ourselves.
So we'll be able to save data and visualize them in a nice way.
Let's start with the HTTP protocol.